mystrands.com 2010-09-14

# Support - Privacy Policy on Strands

## Strands Privacy Policy

Strands Labs, Inc. and its affiliates (“Strands”) respect your privacy. This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) is effective as of September 16, 2008. It explains how we collect and use the personal information you may provide to us, and it will help you make informed decisions when using our websites and services. It applies to all the websites and services offered by Strands, including strands.com, mystrands.com, musicstrands.com, money.strands.com, bizsolutions.strands.com, partystrands.com, indie.mystrands.com, labs.mystrands.com and mystrands.tv (collectively, Strands’ “Sites” or “Services”). Some of our Services have additional privacy terms made available to you in connection with your use of those Services. If a Service has additional privacy terms, they supercede any conflicting terms in this Policy.

This privacy policy covers the following areas:

  * what information we collect through the Services; 
  * how we use the information; 
  * with whom we may share the information; 
  * what choices you have about our collection, use and disclosure of the information; 
  * what security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under our control; and 
  * how you can correct any inaccuracies in the information. 

Strands adheres to the [US Safe Harbor Privacy Principles](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/) of Notice, Choice, Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity, Access and Enforcement. You can see our certification on the [Safe Harbor List](http://web.ita.doc.gov/safeharbor/shlist.nsf/webPages/safe+harbor+list/). 

#### Information Collection

Strands collects information in several ways. First, we use server logs to collect anonymous, aggregate information (such as browser type, ISP, IP address, referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks) from all visitors to the Sites. Our Sites also use a standard technology called "cookies" to collect information about how the Site is used. Information gathered through cookies may include the pages viewed and the amount of time spent at the Site. This type of information is typically not linked to any personally identifiable information and is used primarily in the aggregate to generate statistical reports about the use of our Site. Strands does reserve the right to connect information collected through its server logs with other personally identifiable information.   
Second, we collect information when you register to use a Service. During registration, you are required to provide only limited information, such as a valid email address, screen name and password. For most Strands Sites, providing other personally identifiable information is optional. Additional information is required to register for and use certain Sites, including money.strands.com and bizsolutions.strands.com. We will collect and retain the information you provide during registration. We may also connect the information you provide to us with information provided by third parties, in order to give you a better user experience. Subject to applicable law, we own the information collected via the Sites and Services.

#### More about Cookies

A cookie is a file stored on your computer and tied to information about you. Our Sites use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. The session ID cookie terminates once you close the browser. For the persistent cookie, a text file is stored on your computer for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions. If you allow the persistent cookie, our Sites can recognize your computer and your browser can remember your login information for our Sites. If you reject the cookie, your user experience may be limited.

#### Third Party Sites and Cookies

Links to sites other than the Strands Sites may be displayed within our Sites and Services. These other sites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you. Strands does not control and is not responsible for the privacy practices of sites other than the Strands Sites. You should carefully review the privacy policy of any site that solicits personal information from you.

#### Personal information of children under 13

Our Sites and Services are not directed to children, and we do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13 years of age.

#### Service Communications from Strands

We may communicate with you to provide requested services and resolve issues relating to your account. You may not opt out of these service-related communications while you use the service, but you may terminate your use of the service at any time and delete your profile and related information.

#### Marketing Communications from Strands

Within the Strands family of companies, we may share your information with our affiliates (a) for purposes other than direct marketing, and (b) unless you instruct us otherwise, for direct marketing purposes. From time to time we may send notices about products, services, special deals, or newsletters. You may withdraw permission to receive marketing communications at any time; log in to your account and follow the instructions to change your user preferences. You can also opt out by following the instructions at the bottom of any Strands marketing email.

#### Disclosure of Information to Third Parties

**Disclosure by You.** Anyone can search the user community by email address, name or screen name. Therefore, someone who knows or guesses your name or the email address you use to register with us can discover your screen name and see all the posts associated with that screen name. However, your screen name can not be used to obtain your email address, name or other non-profile information you submit at registration.

**Disclosure by Strands.** Strands does not sell, rent or disclose personally identifiable information to any third party not affiliated with us, except for disclosure to service providers who may assist us in such areas as data storage, and in connection with legal proceedings as described below. Information in anonymous, aggregated form may be shared freely, and Strands reserves the right to share aggregated usage information with reputable third parties, including for the purpose of targeting Internet banner advertisements. We may also use aggregated information about users and their preferences, or information that users have already made available to the general public, for demonstration purposes on other public or limited-access test websites.

**Disclosure Required by Law.** We will disclose personal information when required by law, or if we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on us, (b) protect and defend our rights, or (c) protect the rights, property, and other interests of our users or others.

#### Business Transitions

In the event Strands goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, co-branding a product, or selling a portion of its assets, users’ personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred.

#### Security

Strands takes reasonable precautions in accordance with industry standards to protect our users' information. When you submit information to us via our Sites but you choose not to make that information accessible to others, the information is protected both online and off-line. Such information is subject to restricted access in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job are granted access to such personally identifiable information. All employees are also kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. The servers that store nonpublic personally identifiable information are in a secure environment, in a locked facility. Strands also maintains notification procedures as part of its information security policy for notifying you in the event of a data security breach. If Strands experiences a data security breach and is required to notify you under applicable law, Strands will notify you by electronic mail using the e-mail address you have provided. You are responsible for ensuring that your contact information is current and correct. To review or change your information, log in to the Site and update the information under the Preferences tab.

#### Deleting or Deactivating Personal Information

You may deactivate your Strands account at any time by emailing your request to [support@strands.com](mailto:support@strands.com). Your profile and any posts you have made will be removed from our Site. However, your posts and information may remain in our backup systems.

#### Notification of Changes

If we decide to change this Policy, we will post those changes here and in other places we deem appropriate, so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If, however, we are going to use users' personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users via email and by posting a notice on the applicable Site for 30 days.

#### Non-U.S. Users

Strands processes and stores personal information in the United States of America. If you are outside the United States, information you submit to Strands will be transferred out of your country and into the United States. When you agree to our Terms and Conditions, you agree to such transfers, and you warrant and represent that it is lawful for you to transfer the information into the United States.

#### Contact Information

You can send questions about our privacy or security practices to [support@strands.com](mailto:support@strands.com) or Strands Labs, Inc., 760 SW Madison Ave., Ste. 106, Corvallis OR 97333.
